minecraftlist.org 2019-04-12

# Minecraft Server List - Minecraft List

This page outlines the types of personal information received and collected by MinecraftList.org and how it is used. 

**Data Security**

We will take reasonable steps to protect the personal data under our control from unauthorised access, improper use and disclosure. Even though we have taken reasonable steps to protect your data whilst it is being transmitted, we cannot guarantee the security of any data transmitted to us by the internet and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your data, we will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access. 

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, MinecraftList.org makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyse trends, administer the site, track users movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

MinecraftList.org does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customise webpage content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on MinecraftList.org. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to MinecraftList.org and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL: http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html 

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:

Google Adsense 

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to display the advertisements and links that appear on MinecraftList.org. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalise the advertising content that you see. MinecraftList.org has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. MinecraftList.org's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us via our email – admin[[email protected]](https://minecraftlist.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
